彼得：我想我们都对道德是什么有一个相当朦胧的想法。我们相信本质上
Peter: I think we all have a fairly hazy idea about what ethics is. We believe intrinsically
道德是一件好事。我对这个主题的了解非常有限，所以我会
that ethics is a good thing. My knowledge of the topic is incredibly limited, so I'd
我想介绍我的同事教授道格贝克，他更了解道德而不是道德
like to introduce my colleague professor Doug Baker, who knows way more about ethics than
我做。欢迎道格！
I do. Welcome Doug!
道格：谢谢你，彼得。很高兴来到这里。
Doug: Thank you, Peter. A pleasure to be here.
彼得：道格，我对道德是什么没有清醒的认识。当我听到道德这个词时，
Peter: So Doug, I don't have a crisp sense of what ethics is. When I hear the word ethics,
我想到各种各样的事情;是非，善与恶，道德，价值观，行为。
I think of all kinds of things; right and wrong, good and evil, morals, values, behaviors.
你能为我解开一些这些事吗？
Can you untangle some of these things for me?
道格：是的。我认为彼得，当我教授道德时，我想首先开始教授什么
Doug: Yes. I think Peter, when I teach ethics, I like to first start off with teaching what
道德不是。
ethics is not.
彼得：好的。
Peter: Okay.
道格：要开始消极，通常这不是一件好事，但我开始吧
Doug: To start off on the negative, usually that's not a good thing, but I start off on
否定的。它不是什么;是不是价值观。这不是宗教。这是件事
the negative. What it is not; is that it's not values. It is not religion. It is something
从根本上说，它构成了整个社会的基础，它是所有宗教的基础，它超越了文化。
fundamentally, that underlies all of society, it underlies all of religion and it transcends culture.
彼得：所有社会，所有宗教，所有文化？这是一个全球性的事情？
Peter: So all societies, all religions, all cultures? It's a global thing?
道格：它的全球性。它实际上是道德哲学，它为我们提供了指导。伦理
Doug: Its global. It is actually the philosophy of morality and it offers us a guide. Ethics
为我们提供正确的指导。
offers us a guide as to the right thing to do.
彼得：好的。
Peter: Okay.
道格：所以，价值观是一个信仰的星座，是我们是谁，是它的混合体
Doug: And so, values are a constellation of beliefs, an amalgam of who we are, and it's
具有文化特色的价值观及其具体情境。换句话说，其中的值
culturally specific values and it's contextually specific. In other words, the values within
1800年的澳大利亚文化与现在澳大利亚文化的价值观完全不同。
Australian culture in say 1800 are quite different than the values in Australian culture now.
彼得：但随着时间的推移道德有变化吗？
Peter: But have ethics changed over the time?
道格：不，但价值观会发生变化。
Doug: No, but values change.
彼得：所以这是一种解释？
Peter: So it's an interpretation?
道格：价值观树立了文化的规范，它们是一种执行道德的方式。但
Doug: Values set the norms of the culture, and they are a way of enforcing ethics. But
正如我所说，伦理学超越了它们，超越了所有文化。因此，价值再次持续到
ethics transcends them, to all cultures as I said. So, values again are continuous to
时间，但这在道德方面没有变化。什么应该是正确的
time, but that doesn't change in terms of ethics. What ought to be the right thing to
做什么，做正确的事情是由道德推理决定的。
do, what is the right thing to do is determined by moral reasoning.
彼得：所以人们长期以来一直在思考道德，也许是最长的道德
Peter: So people have been thinking about ethics for a long, long time, maybe the longest
人们想过的活动或主题。他们都同意吗？
activity or topic that people have thought about. Do they all agree?
道格：没有。但是，请听，道德理论有一定程度。这是一个巨大的领域和方面
Doug: No. But, listen, there are degrees in ethical theory. It is a huge area and in terms
我们如何以道德的方式进行，通常有两种不同的思想流派。有
of how we proceed ethically, there's generally two different schools of thought. There's
目的论和那里的道义论，如果我们看看这两种不同的思想流派
teleology and there's deontology, and if we look at those two different schools of thought
在道德推理方面，他们会谈到我们应该如何进行以及我们应该如何进行
in terms of moral reasoning, they'd come to how we should proceed and how we ought to
行为不同。
act differently.
彼得：好的，让我经历这两个。
Peter: Okay so run me through these two.
道格：好的。所以第一次目的论看好事，做正确的事;什么是
Doug: Okay. So first teleology looks at the good thing, the right thing to do; what's
好到最后，它看着获得好的过程，以及与之争论
good in the end, and it looks at the process of getting what's good, and the argument with
目的论是，我们通过做正确的事情并产生最大的东西来进入未来
teleology is, we proceed into the future by doing the right thing and producing the greatest
好。因此，它的论点是，它不是过程而是产品，而且它是
good. And so, the argument in it is, it's not the process but the product, and it's
也称为结果主义。就功利主义者边沁和米尔而言
also called consequentialism. And in terms of the utilitarians Bentham and Mill in the
1840年代，1850年代和1860年代，功利主义通过观察引入了这一道德分支
1840's, 1850's and 1860's, utilitarianism is brought in this branch of ethics by looking
最大的好处是最大的。所以，无论你做什么，都应该建立最大的
at the greatest good for the greatest number. So, whatever you do should build the largest
幸福的程度，所以最终的结果是来了。
degree of happiness, so the end result is what comes.
彼得：那不是关于个人，而是关于更大的利益？
Peter: So it's not about the individual, it's about the greater good?
道格：正确。
Doug: Correct.
彼得：好的。
Peter: Okay.
道格：是的，完全正确。因此，如果我们建造一座电力大坝，目标就是建设
Doug: Yeah, exactly right. So, if we build a dam for power, the objective is to build
为一个国家的工业化提供动力的工业水库，事实
an industrial reservoir for power for the industrialisation of a nation, and the fact
我们不得不搬出两百个农民或几个村民并不重要。
that we have to move out two hundred farmers or a couple of villagers doesn't matter.
彼得：因为更大的好处？
Peter: Because of the greater good?
道格：重要的是。
Doug: It's what counts.
彼得：好的。因此，在工程术语中，您会说这将取决于您的成本函数。
Peter: Okay. So, in an engineering term then, you'd say that would depend on your cost function.
这取决于你施加在电力和村庄幸福的重量。
It would depend on the weights that you applied to electricity and to the happiness of the village.
道格：当然。因此，它成为衡量市场和非市场变量的案例。
Doug: Absolutely. And so, it becomes a case of measuring market and non market variables.
但最大数量的最大好处通常是你在很多方面看到的论点
But the greatest good for the greatest number is often the argument you see in a lot of
大型项目。那是的，我们知道，我们知道我们必须在这里影响你，我们知道这一点
mega projects. That, yeah we know, we know we have to affect you here and we know this
社区受到影响但是，对于更多的人来说，这很重要。
community's getting impacted but, for the greater number, it's important.
彼得：告诉我另一个分支。
Peter: Tell me about the other branch.
道格：另一个分支真的看着这个过程。道义论是一个完整的思想领域，
Doug: The other branch really looks at the process. Deontology is a whole area of thought,
从不能开始向右前进，看着这个过程，
starting with can't and moving forward right through the rolls, that looks at the process,
而论证是过程与善是分开的。所以好的是分开的
and the argument is that the process and the good are separated. So what is good is separate
从过程的正确性。
from the correctness of the process.
彼得：你是怎么到达那里的？
Peter: It's how you get there?
道格：正确。
Doug: Correct.
彼得：好的
Peter: Okay
道格：所以这个论点实际上是我们如何做到的，它是至关重要的，以及道德指导
Doug: So the argument is in fact how we do it, it's critical, and that moral guidance
至于我们如何做到这一点有所不同。
as to how we do it makes the difference.
彼得：你能举个例子吗？
Peter: Can you give me an example.
道格：所以在公众参与方面，这个论点是，例如，任何政府
Doug: So in terms of public participation, the argument is, for example, any government
实际上，当他们心中有一个大型项目时，请继续进行。
would actually, when they have a large project in their mind go ahead and do it in the past.
但现在我们有一个过程，通过这个过程来告知公众，使公众融入社会
But now we have a process by which to inform the public, to integrate the public, to make
关于这是否是最佳途径，以及更多人参与的决定
the decisions as to whether this is the best path to go, and more people are involved in
决策过程，以及公众参与和利益相关者的参与
the decision making process, and as a result public participation and stakeholder participation
因此而蓬勃发展。但这个分支的关键-道义论;约翰罗尔斯
is bloomed as a result of this. But the key with this branch - deontology; John Rawls
可能是20世纪最着名的哲学家，真正看过一个理论
is probably the most well known philosopher of the 20th Century, really looked at a theory
正义和论点是，这里重要的是对个人和我们的正义
of justice, and the argument was, what counts here is justice for the individual, and we
我们的决定基于什么是适合个人的，而不是伤害个人。
base our decisions on what's right for the individual and not to harm the individual.
彼得：好的，那么一个分支就是更大的好处，但是我们可能会定义其他分支
Peter: Okay so one branch then is the greater good of however we might define that, other
分支对个人来说是最好的。
branch is what's best for the individual.
道格：当然。
Doug: Absolutely.
彼得：我可以挑选吗？这两种道德都没有比另一种好吗？
Peter: So I can pick and choose? No one of both ethics is better than the other?
道格：正确。你可以相应地证明它的合理性。例如，在你的结果主义中
Doug: Correct. And you can justify it accordingly. For example, in consequentialism when you
看看积极的歧视，换句话说，首先是优先聘用
look at positive discrimination, in other words a preferential hiring of say, first
国家或原住民超过其他申请人，或雇用妇女超过其他申请人
nations or aboriginal people over top of other applicants, or the hiring of women over the
男人最喜欢男人。现在的争论是积极的歧视是
top of men, in preference to men. Now the argument is that positive discrimination is
在结果主义论证中证明是合理的，因为过去存在问题
justified in a consequentialist argument, in that there has been problems in the past
关于我们如何对待女性以及如何解雇她们。我们现在可以纠正这个问题
with respect to how we treated women and how we fired. We can rectify that in the present
特别注重雇用他们并违反正义原则，但是
by specifically focusing on hiring them and violating the principle of justice, but the
最终的结果是，我们将有50％的女性在工作场所。
end result is that we'll have 50% women in the work place.
彼得：是的。
Peter: Yeah.
道格：你和我在一起？所以这是一个结果论证。现在，牙医学家会冒犯他人
Doug: You're with me? So that's a consequentialist argument. Now a deontologist would take offence
因为你违反了公平。因此，一个结果主义者的观点
to that, because you're violating fairness. And so, a consequentialist's perspective then
记住了最终的结果，并再次考虑到了更大的利益。所以你可以从双方争论。
has the end result in mind, and again the greater good in mind. So you can argue from both sides.
彼得：道格，所有这一切，我如何将道德思维付诸实践？
Peter: So Doug, given all of that, how do I put ethical thinking into practice?
道格：没有公式，但所有道德准则都有一个基本的基础。
Doug: There's no formula but there's a fundamental kind of basis for all moral codes.
彼得：好的。
Peter: Okay.
道格：它再次取决于个人和个人的权利。首先是
Doug: It hinges around again, the individual and the rights of the individual. First there's
自治的结构-个人自己选择而不是自己选择的权利
the construct of autonomy - the right of the individual to make their own choice and not
违反这一点。其次，有一种男性的结构-没有伤害。
to violate that. Secondly, there's a construct of maleficence - to do no harm.
彼得：好的。
Peter: Okay.
道格：这是围绕着医生的道德准则。它是围绕非恶意形成的。
Doug: And it's the ethical code that surrounds doctors. It's formed around non-maleficence.
然后是有益的，即帮助，帮助。其次，或者最后，就是这个
Then there's beneficence, which is to help, to aid. Secondly, or lastly, there's this
正义的概念和那是罗尔斯的方法。你必须公平。公平原则至关重要。
notion of justice and that's Rawls approach. You must have fairness. The fairness principle is critical.
彼得：公平是一个绝对的概念吗？
Peter: Is fairness an absolute concept?
道格：是的，确实如此。如果你看一下功利主义理论和帕累托，它就可以被权衡
Doug: Yes, it is. And it can be weighed if you look at the utilitarian theory and Pareto
经济学-他们在这种结构中公平，在公平和不公平方面
economics - they lay fairness in that construct, in terms of what is fair and what isn't and
我们如何确定公平性。因此，它翻译，大部分伦理理论直接翻译
how do we determine fairness. So, it translates, much of this ethical theory translates directly
进入经济理论和功利主义理论。所以引入它是如此令人着迷
into economic theory and utilitarian theory. So it's fascinating how it's all brought in
并通过它了解我们如何看待世界以及我们如何评估世界。
and through it into the how we see the world and how we evaluate the world.
彼得：所以这不仅仅是一些抽象的概念，它可以付诸实践而且是它的基础
Peter: So it's not just some abstract notion, it can be put into practice and it underpins
我们社会中非常重要的事情。
really important things in our society.
道格：绝对是！没有什么比良好的道德理论更有用了。
Doug: Absolutely! There's nothing more applied than a good ethical theory.